您
you
好吧，让我们今天开始，我想谈谈
alright let's get started today I want
to talk about
堆栈，而我们查看本文的原因是它涉及三个方面
stack and the reason we're looking at
this paper is that it touches on three
我觉得很有趣的问题可能是最低层的
questions that I find quite interesting
one is maybe at the lowest level how to
建立一个从名称映射的命名系统或真正的公钥基础结构
build a naming system or really a public
key infrastructure that maps from names
公钥，这就像一个非常重要的问题，没人会遇到
to public keys and this is like a very
important question nobody has ever
真正找到了一种令人信服的方式来建立通用的全球公众
really figured out a convincing way to
build a general-purpose global public
关键基础架构或PKI，因此在此领域的任何进展都是
key infrastructure or PKI so any
progress in this area with the is
有趣的是，我对块堆栈感兴趣的另一个原因是
interesting another reason I'm
interested in block stack is that it's a
您知道的非加密货币使用区块链，所以这只是一个有趣的事情
non cryptocurrency use of a blockchain
you know so it's just an interesting
质疑区块链是否对金融以外的其他有用
question whether block chains are useful
for anything other than than financial
东西，最后，您可能知道最有趣的是：
stuff and finally and you know maybe
most interestingly block sects really a
关于如何提供Internet服务的非常不同的体系结构的建议
proposal for a very different
architecture for how Internet services
或真正的网站应该如何构建非常不同的网站
or really web sites how websites
ought to be constructed very different
从它们现在的构造方式来看，它们的特性完全不同，您知道
from the way they're constructed now is
quite different properties and you know
这个想法是，也许是那种布洛克麻袋
the idea is that maybe the the kind of
approach brock sack
可能会产生一些在某些方面比您更了解的网站
takes might yield websites that are are
better you know in some ways than
当前的网站现在像一个真实的系统一样被阻止，有一家公司
current web sites now blocks likes a
real system there's a company that's
开发一些应用程序正在使用的程序，我只有一些用户
developing it that's in use by some
applications i'm just have some users
但是实际上您知道您应该将其视为道德上的进步，然后
however it's really you know you should
view it as moral work-in-progress then
这是他们一直在开发并使之更好的最终答案
kind of this is the final answer they've
been developing it and making it better
几年过去了，我认为这真的不是很多
over some years now i don't think it's
really to the point where very many
人们会决定放弃现在建立网站的方式，而转向
people would decide to abandon the way
they build websites now and switch to
块堆栈，但重要的是有人在那里探索如何
block stack but it's very important that
somebody out there is exploring how
情况可能会有所不同并且更好，而块堆栈是
things could be different and better and
block stack is one of a number of
试图朝着不同方向推动的不同项目
different projects that are trying to
push in a different direction for the
网站的总体架构还不错，因此块堆栈的优势
overall architecture of web sites all
right so the the pitch from block stack
人们应该建立体面的
is that people ought to be building
decent
应用程序的去中心化是什么意思
applications so what does decentralize
mean sort of an idea that's been in the
播出了几年，我认为也许最好的总结是
air for a couple years now I think maybe
the best summary is that it's
以将数据所有权移出的方式构建的应用程序
applications that are built in a way
that moves ownership of data out of
您知道的集中控制网站，就像普通的Web服务器一样，或者
centrally controlled websites you know
like ordinary web servers and one way or
另一个将对用户信息的控制更多地放到了用户自己的手中
another puts control of users
information more into the users own
以便说用户实际上拥有自己的东西有点现实
hands so that it's sort of realistic to
say that users actually own their own
数据，而不是您知道Facebook或Gmail或本质上是谁
data instead of you know Facebook or
Gmail or whoever sort of essentially
拥有他们的数据对他们的成功和有趣的属性
owning their data for them the success
and the interesting properties of
比特币是推动该领域近期活动的重要因素
Bitcoin have been a lot of what's driven
the recent activity in this area it's
一种古老的想法可以追溯到至少出现在像Nutella这样的计划上
kind of an old idea dates back at least
appeared appear on schemes like Nutella
和Napster距今大约20年前，甚至更远，但是比特币
and Napster from around 20 years ago and
further back than that but Bitcoin
确实促使人们对此进行认真思考，并有点
really prompted people to think hard
about this and to sort of have a bit
更加相信可以实现这些想法，所以我想
more faith that these kinds of ideas
could be realized all right so I want to
首先概述一下，您知道当前网络的一种集中式典型
kind of outline first what a sort of
centralized typical you know current web
该网站看起来像是在谈论为什么有些人不是很满意
site looks like talk a bit about why
some people aren't really pleased with
当前网站的工作方式，然后概述在
the way current websites work and then
outline how things might work under a
像块堆栈这样的分散方案，所以这实际上是当前网站的视图
decentralized scheme like block stack so
this is really current websites the view
您有很多用户坐在浏览器前吗？他们有一个互联网
is you got a much users sitting in front
of browsers and there's a internet they
所有人都在与互联网交谈，您那里有一些网站，您知道也许是
all talk to the internet you have some
website out there you know maybe it's
例如Gmail或其他内容，而Gmail拥有一堆由
say Gmail or something and Gmail has a
bunch of web servers that are owned by
Gmail归任何网络服务所有，并位于网络背后
Gmail right owned by whatever the web
services and sitting behind the web
服务器是某种数据库，对我们来说是一张熟悉的图片
servers is some kind of database
it's kind of familiar picture for us
通过这些个人用户，该数据库保存用户数据，例如
through these individual users this
database holds the users data like if
您使用Gmail，您知道您认识的用户。Gmail位于Gmail的
you use Gmail you know your you know
user ones Gmail is sitting in Gmail's
数据库，您知道这是Gmail拥有的数据库服务器，
database somewhere you know this is a
database server the Gmail owns and
这实际上控制着Gmail运作方式的逻辑
that's control over the kind of logic
for how Gmail operates essentially sits
拥有生物的网络服务器中的所有权归Gmail所有，并且与
in the web servers that own bio are
owned by Gmail and sort of talk to the
数据库以摆脱您的数据，所以完全没有任何东西
database to get out of your data alright
so there's like totally nothing
令人惊讶的是，您知道这是几乎每个网站的工作方式，这是
surprising here and you know this is the
way almost every website works this is
通常是一些JavaScript或其他内容，并位于用户浏览器中，但所有
often some JavaScript or something and
sitting in the users browsers but all
关键的事情是坐在Web服务器或某种
the kind of critical stuff is sitting in
web servers or some kind of servers that
该网站打呵欠，您知道，所以当天有四个不同的网站
the website yawns you know so four
different websites the day on the
数据库将成为博客文章或邮件之类的东西，或者您知道自己的评论
database is gonna be things like blog
posts or mail or you know comments you
在其他人的reddit或其他内容上发布，或者也许是您的照片
post on other people's reddit or
something or maybe it's your photos your
日历我是您的病历或其他很多数据
calendar my is your medical records or
something there's a lot of data that's
在各种不同的网站上都可以找到用户
out there at various different websites
that is in some sense you know the users
数据确实是用户Gmail，但它确实是Gmail或具有控制权的数据
data like it's really the users Gmail
but gosh it's Gmail or that has control
可以控制用户评论和其他人的评论
over it or reddit that has control over
the users comments and other people's
现在的文章，此设置为SuperDuper
articles
now this setups been SuperDuper
成功的原因是坐这很容易的原因之一
successful it's actually and one of the
reasons to sit it's extremely easy to
您知道的程序，所有逻辑都能听到和运行，并且服务器由Gmail控制
program you know all the logic hears and
running and servers controlled by Gmail
他们可以通过诸如续集数据库之类的东西与这些数据库交流
they can talk to these databases trough
in things like sequel databases that
非常灵活的查询界面，对于可以存储的数据没有任何限制
very flexible query interfaces there's
like no restrictions on what data can be
就像您知道的那样被访问，所以假设这是在这里运行的eBay
accessed like you know so supposing this
is a eBay that's running here you know
现在，用户出价位于eBay的数据库服务器中，
the users bids are sitting in eBay's
database server now the bids are quite
如果我要竞标某些我不希望其他用户竞标的东西，则为私人权利
private right if I'm bidding on
something I don't want other users to
看到它，但是对eBay的Web服务器可以看到的内容没有任何限制
see it but there's no restrictions on
what eBay's web servers can look at they
都可以在自己的数据库中查看出价，也可以查看其他
can all look at the bids in the in their
own database they can look at other
人们的出价找到最高出价，实际上没有任何限制，因此
people's bids find the highest bid
there's really no restrictions so it's
对于Web开发人员来说非常非常方便，而且非常
very very convenient
for web developers and is very
成功，因此从这个角度来看，我们应该对您持怀疑态度
successful and so from that point of
view we should be you know skeptical
其他任何事情都可能成功或超越它，但
that anything else could possibly be
this successful or overtake it but the
为什么您可能认为当前的设置不完美的原因是
reason why you might not think this
current setup is perfect well there's a
一堆用户可能不满意的原因之一是，如果我存储我的
bunch of reasons that users might be
dissatisfied one is that if I store my
Gmail中的邮件我真的必须使用Gmail的界面来获取它
mail in Gmail I really have to use
Gmail's interface to get at it
你知道也许他们提供了其他一些途径来实现这一目标，但我通常
you know maybe they provide some other
ways of getting at it but I generally
没有太多的自由，例如Gmail为我自己设定了规则
don't have a lot of freedom like Gmail
sets the rules for how I get at my own
正确的电子邮件，所以我可能有点恼火，这是我的电子邮件，但您知道我
email right so I might be a little bit
irritated it's my email but you know I
不要选择我使用的界面我不能只使用任何软件
don't get to choose what interface I use
I can't just use any software Lee pretty
一定是Gmail提供或Gmail支持的软件
much has to be software that Gmail
provides or Gmail supports for
诸如Facebook之类的情况，其他人有时可能会看到我的数据
situations like maybe Facebook where
other people might sometimes see my data
确实是为谁设置访问我的数据的规则的网站
is really the website that gets to set
the rules for who gets access to my data
或者我怎么能控制访问和网站经常变得晦暗
or how if at all I can control that
access and websites often are bit murky
关于他们对如何执行这些东西的承诺，如果这是
about their promises about how they
enforce this stuff and again if it's the
用户数据，例如是我的照片或帖子还是真的
users data like if it's my photos or my
posts or something it's really kind of
不太好，我对网站的功能没有太多控制权
not that great that I don't have too
much control over what the website can
用它做另一件事，人们抱怨当前的设置
do with it another thing that people
complain about with the current set up
该网站可以嗅探我的东西，例如Gmail想浏览
is that the website can sniff on my
stuff like Gmail wants to look through
我的邮件，他们可能有很好的理由，也许他们正在训练垃圾邮件
my mail they might have good reasons for
maybe they were training their spam
生成器，这样就可以了，但是您知道也许正在看我的电子邮件来思考
generators so that's okay but you know
maybe looking at my email to think about
向我显示广告或您知道告诉他们的广告客户什么
showing me advertisements or to you know
tell their advertising customers what
人们对这几天感兴趣，更糟的是，
people are interested in these days
worse the there's a chance that some of
在网站上工作的员工已经腐败，甚至可能在偷窥
the employees who work at the web site
are corrupt and maybe snooping on
人的数据是出于个人原因，因此可能是公司或公司
people's data for personal reasons so
that maybe the company maybe the company
该网站的运营完全是面面俱到，但不一定能坐下来
that runs the website is perfectly
aboveboard but can't necessarily sit
声称并非所有员工都在或跟随所有员工
claim that it's not always true that all
the employees are or following all the
反正规则，所以人们有很多你知道的，或者有些人有
rules anyway so people have a lot
kind of you know or some people have
对当前系统在更多设计上的工作方式持保留态度
reservations about the way the current
system works at a kind of more design
技术层面来查看正在发生什么的一种方法是主界面
technical level one way to view what's
going on here is that the main interface
这里是整个网站和浏览器之间，所以是HTML
here is between the entire website and
the browser's so there's it's HTML
在这里通常是网站和
that's flowing back and forth between
here typically the websites and the
数据库有点集成在界面的这一侧，并且所有
database are sort of integrated on this
side of the interface and all the
浏览器真正经常看到的是这种HTML的最终打包形式
browser really gets to see often is this
HTML kind of final packaged form of the
数据，并且您知道这是一个非常面向用户界面的表示形式hTML
data and you know it's a very user
interface oriented representation hTML
是，有点点头无话可说，你知道戴夫数据本身还是
is and sort of Nod has nothing to say
about you know Dave the data itself or
如何控制数据以及更有趣的界面以及位置
how the data is controlled and the much
more interesting interface and where
您知道整个讨论都在进行，这是更多
this you know a whole discussion is kind
of going is that this is a much more
有趣的界面，因为它更接近数据，但在标准中
interesting interface because it's much
closer to the data but in the standard
设置那里没有真正的边界，尽管这是内部的
setup there's no real boundary there
though this is sort of the internal
生意如何运作是网站的内部生意好吗
business how this works is the internal
business of the website all right so
这是现有计划，计划是块堆栈的计划
that's the existing plan the plan the
kind of plan that block stack is
提议，因此对于去中心化应用程序有很多想法
proposing and so there's a number of
kind of ideas for how decentralized apps
可能有效，这是其中的一种，所以我还不称之为块堆栈
might work this is kind of one of them
so I'm not gonna call it block stack yet
因为它是一个非常简化的版本，我们只是说这是一个
because it's it's kind of much a very
simplified version we'll just say it's a
分散式架构，这里的游戏是您知道我们仍然有一个
decentralized architecture and here the
game is that you know we still have a
一群用户和用户运行，您知道iPad或浏览器之类的东西
bunch of users and users run you know
iPads or browsers or something
但我们将采用这种新的分散方案，将所有
but we're gonna in this new
decentralized scheme we're gonna put all
的应用程序代码将在用户计算机的客户端计算机中运行
of the app code is gonna run in the
client machines in the users machines
所以这更像是一种传统，或者就像你知道的
and so this is much more like a sort of
traditional or it's like you know
从iPad上的应用程序商店下载应用程序或购买某种老式PC
downloading an app from the app store on
an iPad or buying sort of old-style PC
硬件，例如购买Microsoft Word的副本，它只能在笔记本电脑上运行
hardware like buying a copy of Microsoft
Word this just runs on your laptop just
购买一些在笔记本电脑上运行的软件，以便不再运行该应用程序
buy some software you run on your laptop
so no longer running the application
Web服务器中的代码，那么您知道是否要做的就是使用您的数据
code in web servers well you know if all
you want to do is use data on your
在您自己的笔记本电脑上存储您自己的数据，然后我们完成了，但实际上是什么
laptop your own data on your own laptop
and then we're done but what's really
有趣的是您知道基于Web的基于Internet的应用程序
interesting about you know web-based
what about internet based applications
是您可以将数据存储在云中，这意味着您可以
is that you can store your data in the
cloud and that means you can if you have
大多数人可以使用的多种设备可以从以下任何一种设备获取数据
multiple devices which most people do
you can get at your data from any of
您的设备（可能是iPhone以及笔记本电脑），如果有
your devices from your maybe your iPhone
as well as your laptop and if you've
以某种方式将数据存储在云中意味着您可以与其他人共享数据
stored data in the cloud somehow that
means you can share data with other
人员并构建像您这样的多用户应用程序，您可能知道eBay或您的reddit或
people and build multi-user applications
like you know eBay maybe your reddit or
谁知道什么共享日历，所以去中心化愿景的另一半
who knows what shared calendars so the
other half of the decentralized vision
将会有某种类型的云存储系统的存储系统
is that there's going to be a storage
system some sort of cloud storage system
在那里，我们的意思是说我的意思是您可以购买的某种服务
out there by which we mean I mean some
sort of service that you can buy maybe
您可以从Amazon AWS或谁知道仅在哪里存储的地方知道
you know from Amazon AWS or
who-knows-where which was just store
为您提供数据，您可以将数据保留在其中，这是它们为您存储的数据
data for you you can stick data in it
it's your data they store for you back
它希望杜米某种访问
it up
dumi hopefully some sort of access
控制，以便人们是否无法理解它，然后您可以稍后检索它
control so whether people can't get at
it and then you can retrieve it later
从您的任何设备上获取信息，因此现在，如果我们要建立某种您知道的
from any of your devices and so now if
we're building some sort of you know for
像您这样的单用户应用程序，我只需要编辑一些文档，但是我
single user applications like you know I
just need to edit some documents but I
想要将它们保留在云中，您可能知道用户正在从中购买存储
want to keep them in the cloud you know
maybe user one is buying storage from
该存储服务器可能是亚马逊，而用户2正在购买存储
this storage server maybe it's Amazon
and user two is buying storage from
也许是Google的云存储系统来存储我自己的数据
maybe Google's cloud storage system
for my own data I just talked to my own
我的应用程序代码通过Internet与服务存储服务对话
my application code talks across the
internet to the service storage service
我购买存储空间大概是为我本人和用户讲类似的话
that I buy storage from presumably pay
for it myself and user to talk similarly
到他们的存储服务，但如果我们运行的应用程序允许
to their storage service but if we run
applications that are built to allow
用户共享数据，那么就有可能，如果我会说话
users to share data then there's the
possibility that if I know how to talk
给您存储服务，我可以运行一个应用程序，读取它们
to you to storage service I can run an
application that reads data that they
也请允许我阅读，以便您知道是否要构建某种形式的
allow me to read as well so you know if
you wanted to build some sort of a
Facebook喜欢这个应用程序上的东西会知道谁是我的朋友
Facebook like thing on this the
application would know who my friends
是并联系我的朋友存储区以查找更新或照片，或者谁
are and reach out to my friends storage
looking for updates or photos or who
知道我朋友存储在自己的存储中的内容，这意味着我
knows what that my friends have stored
in their own storage so that means I
而不是在他的新模型中接触Facebook网站，而是
instead of contacting with Facebook's
website instead in his new model I would
从Facebook下载一个应用程序并运行它，该应用程序会知道如何
download an app from Facebook and run it
and that app would sort of know how to
找到我的朋友，看看他们存储的数据，您是否知道我的
find my friends and look at the data
that they are storing and you know if my
朋友将照片上传到他们的存储中，实际上仍然是他们的存储
friend uploads a photo to their storage
it's really still it's their storage
他们为此付款，这是他们的照片，他们可以在Facebook上使用它，或者他们
they're paying for it it's their photo
they can use it with Facebook or they
也可以将其与其他应用程序一起使用，因为这些应用程序确实
could use it with other applications too
because the applications are really
现在与数据完全分开，而不是合并到
quite separate now from the from the
data instead of being combined in the
好的现有架构，所以现在有点技术层面
existing architecture all right so now
sort of a technical level the this is
现在存储接口现在是主接口，所以我们有了某种
now the storage interface is now the
main interface so now we have some sort
put get或readwrite或谁知道哪个接口作为主接口
of put get or readwrite or who knows
what interface as the main interface
它不再是HTML，它实际上是我们担心的主要界面
it's no longer HTML it's really a
primary interface we were worried about
这是存储风格的界面，这是一个更好写的界面
it's the storage style interface which
is a much nicer interface to write
到HTML的应用程序
applications to then HTML it's
此外，正如我所提到的，该架构中有很多地方
furthermore as I mentioned there's a
much in this architecture where users
真正拥有并为存储组织付费，这是一个更清晰的概念
really own and pay for an organizing on
storage there's a much clearer notion of
数据实际上是由用户拥有并像您一样由用户控制
data being actually owned by the user
and controlled by the user much like you
在笔记本电脑或雅典娜中拥有数据
own the data on your laptop or in your
Athena
正如您在存储服务中在此说明的那样，
as you ones account here in the storage
service of course there's a number of
但是您现在知道我们对存储系统的设计非常感兴趣
but you know now we're very interested
in the design of the storage system
因为现在这不是隐藏在网站内部
because now this is instead of being
sort of hidden away inside websites this
现在是系统中的主要界面，因此我们非常关心它的功能
is now the primary interface in the
system so we care a lot about how it's
首先设计它是一项非常重要的功能
designed so first of all it's quite
critical that it be a Internet service
在云中，因此我们可以从任何设备获取数据
out in the cloud so we can get at it get
our data from from any of our devices it
实际上，这里所有应用程序代码都需要通用，所以我们
really needs to be general-purpose that
all the application codes here so we
现在不在这种架构中真正拥有特定于应用程序的代码
don't now in this architecture really
get to have applications specific code
在服务器端完全没有，因为这类服务器并不是真的没有
at all on the server side because the
sort of servers aren't don't really have
与应用程序直接相关的任何事情，因此我们需要一个
anything directly to do with
applications so we needed a
通用接口，其功能足以让我们做
general-purpose interface that's
powerful enough for to let us do
无论我们需要什么，这都很难设计，现在我们有了
whatever we need which is a little bit
difficult to design we now have the
必须支付存储空间，现在确实是最显而易见的人
storage has to be paid for and now
really the most obvious person to pay
因为现在是用户自己，也许他们愿意这样做，也许
for it is the user themselves now maybe
they're willing to do that maybe they're
不是我们真的很想有这个分享，但我们也想有私人的
not we'd really like to have this
sharing but we also want to have private
数据，也许我们只想与某些其他人共享我们的数据，所以我们
data and maybe we only want to share our
data with certain other people so we
需要某种原因，所以存储系统中存储接口的一种方式
need some reason so the storage
interface in the storage system one way
或另一个需要相当强大的共享和权限访问控制
or another needs reasonably powerful
sharing and permission access control
系统一个更微妙的问题是，我可能会运行多个应用程序，其中一些
systems a more subtle issue is that I
may run multiple apps some of which I
如果我只是从互联网上下载一些多用户游戏，请不要信任
don't trust right if I just download
some multi-user game from the internet
您知道也许我不希望它在我处于通话状态时能够查看我的电子邮件
you know maybe I don't want it to be
able to look at my email while I'm
玩这个游戏，这意味着除了拥有这种概念
playing that game so that means that as
well as having a notion of sort of this
具有此用户权限的用户，我们可能希望拥有某种子公司
权限，我们不仅可以讨论整个用户，还可以讨论该用户
permissions where we can talk about not
just this user as a whole but this user
当运行一个应用程序具有一定的权限，也许只是游戏
在运行应用程序一时允许该用户访问用户电子邮件
files this user when running application
one is allowed to get at the users email
以及
as well
好吧，然后有趣的是，他们注意到该存储接口
alright then interestingly in their
notices that this storage interface it
说的不像10或20年前那样
says not as much of a stretch as it
might have seen say 10 or 20 years ago
因为那里有许多没有区别的存储服务
because there's a number of storage
services out there that are not unlike
像Amazon s3这样的应用非常广泛，而它却缺少了我们
this like Amazon s3 very widely used and
while it's missing some of the things we
这里肯定需要一个公共存储系统，您可以购买存储
would need here it's definitely a public
storage system you can buy storage you
可以让其他人使用您的存储，但您知道这些存储不具有所有访问权限
can let other people use your storage
you know doesn't have all that access
控制我们想要的东西，但是离这里所需的东西并不太远
control we'd like but it's not too far
from what's needed here and indeed
今天的论文指出，他们可以将存储系统放在一个存储层之上
today's papers observes that they can
layer their storage system on top of one
许多不同的现有存储系统Dropbox也是
of a number of different existing
storage systems Dropbox is also it's
像这样的另一种候选人，因此这不是
another kind of candidate for something
it's like this and therefore this is not
好像在天空中看起来像馅饼，所以这个要点是什么
as sort of pie in the sky as it might
seem ok so what would the point of this
那种建筑，为什么有人会在乎那些可能在乎的人
kind of architecture be why would
anybody care the people who might care
是用户吗，这可能会给用户更多的数据控制权
are the users this this might give users
more more control of their data it may
使用户更轻松地切换应用程序，例如，如果我已经上传了
make it easier for users to switch
applications like if I've uploaded a
一堆照片，我正在使用一个照片组织应用程序或照片编辑应用程序
bunch of photos and I'm using one photo
organization app or photo editing app
由于我的照片与我的应用完全分开，因此我可以切换
since my photos are totally separate
from me from the app I could switch
照片应用程序，并且可能仍然使用我已经使用的所有相同的旧照片集
photo apps and maybe still use all my
same old set of photos that I already
已存储，在此体系结构中可能更容易拥有
have stored it may be easier in this
architecture to have applications that
查看多种数据，您知道我的电子邮件系统可能会很好
look at multiple kinds of data you know
maybe it'd be nice that my email system
能够查看我的日历，反之亦然
be able to look at my calendar and the
other way around may be nice to be able
编写备份软件，无论它们是什么，它们都可以备份我的所有数据
to write backup software they could
backup all of my data no matter what it
有时可能我想
was
periodically maybe I'd like to have a
一种通用的文件浏览器，可以让我查看所有
sort of general-purpose file browser
which would allow me to look at all of
我的数据，而这一切都不可能或不方便，当前的架构
my data and none of this is possible or
convenient and the current architecture
但现在看来，我们已经集中了所有
but it's all seems like within reach now
that we've kind of concentrated all the
将用户拥有的数据存储到存储中，最后可能
users data into storage that that they
own and finally there may well be
优势，因为在隐私和监听方面
advantages since in terms of privacy and
snooping
而不是将我的数据委托给知道它在做什么的Web服务
instead of entrusting my data to a web
service that who knows what it's doing
如果我们正确地玩牌，我们可以对这些应用程序使用加密
with it if we play our cards right we
can use encryption these applications
可以在数据离开客户端计算机之前对其进行加密，因此唯一的事情
can encrypt the data before it leaves my
client machine so that the only thing
这是恢复的数据，您知道我何时读回它
it's a restored here's
to data and you know when I read it back
我将返回加密的数据，然后在我自己的计算机上本地解密，因此
I'll be back encrypted data and then
decrypt it locally on my own machine so
肯特（Kent）存储服务永远不会清楚地看到私有数据，因此这些
Kent storage service never sees private
data in the clear anyway so those are
你们所有人都知道诱人的可能性，为什么您会喜欢为什么
all be sort of you know tantalizing
possibilities why you might like why
用户可能会喜欢这种架构，所以您了解
users might like this architecture all
right so you you know the if you dig
简直就是这些应用程序实际要做的事情
down to the nitty-gritty of what these
applications actually have to do they
您知道您需要制定很多细节，例如需要
you know you would need to work out a
whole lot of details like there needs to
如果您知道我的应用程序是否要查看您的数据，是否需要
be you know if my application is going
to be looking at your data there need to
例如关于数据如何存储在这里的约定，例如，您知道我是否
be sort of conventions for how data
store here for example you know if I'm
将查看您为我们的社交网络应用程序最近发表的帖子
gonna look at your recent posts you made
for our social networking application
您必须将它们存储在您的存储库中，其密钥或名称应为
you have to have stored them in your
storage under a key or a name that my
应用程序知道会尝试查找，因此您必须使用一种
application knows to try to look look
for and you have to use a format that we
所有人都知道，所以您知道如果我们要分享的话会有一些
all understand so you know there's some
if we want to do sharing there's some
确实需要克服的那种标准化障碍
kind of standardization obstacles that
have to be overcome that don't really
大型网站之所以存在，是因为它们只能存储自己喜欢的数据
exist for big websites because they can
just store their data however they like
好的，所以有一个问题是否会对应用程序性能产生不利影响
okay so there's a question does this
adversely affect application performance
绝对这可能会降低性能，因为在过去
absolutely this is likely to be pretty
bad for performance because in the old
方案可以是旧方案，也可以是现有方案
scheme the old scheme can be the
existing scheme can be implemented with
您知道这些大多数的Web服务器可能都具有很高的性能
very high performance you know these
most of the web server may be making
数百个请求数据库，例如当您查看Amazon Web页面时
hundreds of requests the database like
when you look at an Amazon web page for
例如男孩有成千上万的信息
example boy are there hundreds or
thousands of pieces of information that
必须从亚马逊知道的数据库中撤出
had to be pulled out of Amazon's
databases you know when they're all in
同一间机房，数据库中的那些f锁
the same machine room and those fetters
from the database take dozens of
微秒，但如果这些应用程序之一需要跨
microseconds but if one of these
applications needs to reach across the
互联网，您可能知道数百英里之外的一些存储服务
internet you know maybe hundreds of
miles away to some storage service you
知道现在所有东西要花上十倍或一百倍的时间
know it's now everything's going to take
ten or a hundred times as long to fetch
单个数据，所以现在肯定是一个问题，
individual piece of data so now that's
certainly an issue and
你知道这是那种问题，那是一件很聪明的事情
you know it's the kind of that kind of
issue is the kind of thing that clever
设计师可以找到应对方法，所以肯定会是一个问题，但是我的
designers can find ways to deal with so
it would certainly be a problem but my
猜想是为什么该体系结构不存在的总原因
guess is on the sort of total list of
reasons why this architecture is not
要去工作，还有许多其他同样令人不快的难题，
going to work there's a number of other
sort of equally unhappy puzzles and
尽管这绝对会改变人们编写应用程序的方式，因为
although it would absolutely change how
people write applications because
而不是编写会大量使用的应用程序
instead of writing applications that
assemble lots of they use lots and lots
我认为人们需要简化的数据片段
of pieces of data you would have to mean
much more parsimonious I think people
可以解决它，所以对此有任何疑问
could work around it all right all right
so any any questions about this this
整体布局，即区块堆栈正在射击的那种布局
overall arrangement which is the sort of
arrangement that block stack is shooting
为此，我们甚至应该尝试猜测即使在此级别上
for so we should just sort of try to
guess even at this level what kind of
事情可能会出错，原因之一是该接口可能更少
things might go wrong one reason is that
this interface is likely to be less
比数据库接口更灵活，这实际上可以追溯到
flexible than database interfaces and
this actually goes back to the
一点点的表现，你知道可能不会很好，我
performance a little bit you know
weren't probably not going to be well I
这意味着这是要设计的主题，但我们不太可能达成交易
mean this is sort of subject to design
but we're unlikely deals to be
支持超级灵活的续集查询，当然，
supporting super flexible like sequel
queries and certainly it's unlikely that
我们将对其他人的数据进行续集查询，以及
we're going to be doing sequel queries
across other people's data as well as
对于共享数据，这肯定是一个潜在的问题是
ours for shared data so that's certainly
one potential problem is that this
界面可能不太富有表现力，这对于
interface may not be very expressive and
that's going to be painful for
程序员的另一个问题是，这是否可以给用户带来大量流量
programmers another question is could
this give users an amount of traffic
他们可能无法应付，所以这也是一个潜在的问题是
they might not handle yeah so that's
also a potential problem is that you
知道如果您没有非常强大的查询，那么续集在做什么
know if you don't have very powerful
queries much of what sequel is doing
当您与真实的续集数据库进行交谈时，可能是正在寻找原因
when you talk to a real sequel database
is that it may be looking through cause
数据库服务器可以浏览大量数据，但是它只是找到一个
the database server to look through a
lot of data but it just finds the one
回答您正在寻找的可能是所有投票的总和，或者它只是发送的内容
answer you're looking for maybe the sum
of all votes or something it just sends
最后一小段数据，而如果您没有强大的功能
that one little piece of final data back
whereas if you don't have a powerful
查询语言，您可能需要获取很多东西，
query language you may
up having to fetch a lot of stuff and
自己进行过滤或汇总，可能很多
sort of do the filtering or aggregating
yourself and that just might be a lot of
跨人民链接发送的数据
data to be sending across peoples links
是的，所以事情可能会变慢，事情会变慢，这是一个问题
yeah so things might be slower things
would be slower and it's a question
他们是否会变得太慢，也许在将来大家都知道
whether they'd be too slow maybe in the
future in which you know everybody has
宽带互联网，我们有5g手机，而这都不是
broadband internet and we have 5g cell
phones and none of this one it's
性能的东西很重要，或者也许很重要，我不认识另一个
performance stuff will matter or maybe
it'll be important I don't know another
此设置的问题是，有一些网站，例如eBay，
problem with this setup is that there
are some websites like eBay where it's
确实不是所有数据都一定由一个用户拥有的情况，所以
really not the case that all the data is
sort of definitely owned by one user so
以eBay为例，我必须要指出两点，一是某些数据
for eBay for example well I have to have
two points here one is some data is not
所有用户所有的东西都在考虑Reddit的首页，您知道
owned by all users think about the front
page of Reddit right there's you know
Reddit正在运行一些巧妙的算法来选择
there's some clever algorithms that
reddit is running to pick the order of
头版中的项目，我的意思是投票，你知道谁知道
items in the front page I mean to do
with votes and you know who knows what
就像怪异的那些算法在运行，它们从哪里获取数据，也许
like weird those algorithms run and
where do they get the data and maybe
他们在哪里存储有关首页的结论，这就是
where do they store their conclusions
about the front page so that's something
它真的不适合我，你知道也许你可以适合这里，但我会
it doesn't really fit in me you know
maybe you could be fit in here but I'd
有点困难另一种似乎很难的网站
be a little bit hard another kind of
website that seems like could be hard
这是一个海湾，您想与您认识的其他人竞标eBay告诉您
here is is a Bay where you want to bid
against other people you know eBay tells
您是否具有当前的最高出价，这需要eBay查看
you whether you're have the current
highest bid which requires eBay to look
按照别人的出价，然后当您最终中标时，您便知道要支付的金额
at other people's bids and then when you
finally win you know the amount you pay
与第二高的出价有关，但这些出价是您的私人权利
has to do with the second highest bid
but those bids are private right you
不想让其他人看到您的出价，因为这样他们就可以出价1美分
don't want other people to see your bids
because then they can just bid one cent
比您高，并以低成本赢得比赛，因此您知道两个用户两个是
higher than you and win at a low cost so
you know maybe you two user two is
在此处存储了一个出价，但是如果我要针对用户2出价，我们需要
stored a bid here but if my if I'm
bidding against user two and we need
告诉我我是否是中标者
this application to tell me if I'm the
winning bidder that means this
应用程序需要回答这个问题可能需要
application needs in order to answer
that question may need probably needs to
知道用户要出价用户二人出价，这意味着用户要出价
know user to bid user twos bid which
means the users to bid has to be
对我来说可以访问，但是如果我的应用程序代码非常了解，它将在Mike上运行
accessible to me but if my application
code knows it well it's running on Mike
计算机，我可以将其更改为您在您的计算机上运行的代码的通常规则
computer and I can change it right as
the usual rules for code you run in your
自己的计算机，如果我更改应用程序代码以实际显示您的
own computer and if I change my
application code to actually reveal your
出价，那么从eBay尝试的角度来看这完全是作弊
bid then that's totally cheating from
the point of view of what eBay is trying
这样做，所以没有人会相信允许这样做的拍卖系统，这的确是
to do and so nobody would trust auction
system that allowed that so it's really
不清楚，您知道可能会使用一些技巧，但您知道我们是否
unclear you know there's probably tricks
that could be used but you know if we
只需使用这种架构和简单易用的方式，例如eBay等网站
just use this architecture and
straightforward way websites like eBay
需要查看其他人的秘密数据但无需查看数据
that need to look at other people's
secret data but not review of the data
就像是一个难题，我已经提到过那些网站
are quite a puzzle as just like and I
already mentioned that websites that
必须保留自己的数据，例如索引或投票计数，或者经常
have to keep their own data like indexes
or vote counts or something that's often
一个难题也是一个难题，因为这里没有概念，您知道该网站
a puzzle also a puzzle because there's
no notion here of you know the website
本身只有应用程序代码，
itself
there's just application code and
通用用户拥有的存储，因为通常这些东西使您可以
generic user owned storage because
usually these things so you would
可能必须使用一些精简的服务器来增强此功能以运行隐私
probably have to augment this with some
crusted servers to run the privacy
eBay的关键部分或它实际上不适合的模型
critical part of eBay or whatever it
doesn't really fit into the model that
好吧，我要说的另一个坏消息是，如果我
well another thing that's I'm gonna turn
out to be bad news here is that if I if
我有想要与某些人共享的数据，而不是像其他人想要共享的数据
I have data that I want to share with
some people than others like I want to
仅与六到八到四个学生共享数据，但不与外界共享数据，您知道
share data with just six eight to four
students but not outsiders you know how
实际上是强制执行的，您知道我们真的想使用end和
is that actually enforced
you know we'd really like to use end and
加密，因此我们不必信任存储服务器，因为毕竟
encryption so we don't have to trust the
storage server because after all that
是远离当前网站架构的一大动力
was a big motivation for moving away
from the current website architectures
我们不想相信这些云服务，所以我可以
we don't want to have to trust these
sort of these clouds services so I could
加密数据，以便682名四名学生可以读取它，但实际上
encrypt the data so that 682 four
students could read it but it's actually
以任何一种直接的方式来做到这一点都非常困难，你知道我可以
quite difficult to do that in any kind
of straightforward way you know I could
每个加密一次，将您知道的数据加密一百次
encrypt the data a hundred times you
know with once with each of the
六十二个学生密钥，或者也许我可以用一些加密一次
sixty-two for students keys or maybe I
can encrypt the data once with uh some
一种独特的密钥，然后用两个用于学生的密钥对该密钥进行加密，或者
sort of unique key and then encrypt that
key with a two for students keys or
某事，但是然后您遇到一个问题，因此，如果有人放弃课程
something but then you run into a
question so if somebody drops the course
并且您不希望他们能够看到您知道如何制作的数据
and you don't want them to be able to
see the data you know how do you make
确保现在他们看不到数据，因此您可以使用加密保护隐私，但是
sure that now they can't see the data so
you can use encryption for privacy but
一旦您进入一种复杂的多用户应用程序
once you get into a sort of complex
multi user applications with groups of
用户，例如密码学变得很难使用来解决
users for example cryptography becomes
can be quite difficult to use to solve
您的隐私问题还可以，所以这些是系统可能不方便的方法
your privacy problems okay so these are
ways in which the system may be awkward
很难编程，因为编程可能不方便
to awkward to program and because it may
be awkward to program and awkward to
编写可能会泄漏到应用程序集中的功能
program up features that may leak
through into the set of application
您可能也受到限制的功能，这不会使用户感到非常
features you can have being limited also
which it's not going to make users very
高兴的是，这是什么是块堆栈的高级视图
happy either all right this is sort of a
high-level view of what block stack is
有点努力，所以现在让我们把重点放在
kind of working towards so now let's
that's may be focused a little more on
块堆栈，特别是块堆栈实际起源于项目的位置
block stacks specifically where block
stack actually originated as a project
作为一种安全的命名方案，您仍然可以看到我们阅读的论文
was as a secure naming scheme and you
can still see the the paper we read
今天，人们非常关注命名，尽管如果您看一下他们的名字，
today has a lot of preoccupation with
naming although if you look at their
当前的网站以及他们编写的当前内容，这方面的更多内容
current website and the current stuff
they write it's much more about this
分散的架构和应用程序，更不用说命名了
decentralized architecture and
applications and much less about naming
但是名字对他们来说仍然很重要，所以问题是他们是什么
but name is still very important for
them so the question is what are they
您知道他们为什么对名称感兴趣，以及他们需要什么
you know why are they interested in
names and what do they need from a
命名系统，所以他们在论文和
naming system so the kind of names
they're talking about in the paper and
那么块堆栈通常是用户名，这些是真正的人类用户，因此
then block stack in general are user
names these are really human users so
我们在谈论的是像罗伯特·莫里斯（Robert Morris）这样的名字，
we're talking about names like you know
maybe Robert Morris right that's the
他们在谈论的名字，因为您知道那里有
kind of name they're talking about
because you know in there in there are
分散式架构，他们不知道
decentralized architecture they don't
you know those kind of players in the
游戏或用户数据的用户，用户需要控制谁可以看到
game or the users the users of the data
the users need to control who can see
他们的数据，因此他们需要能够为其他用户命名特定的事物
their data so they need to be able to
name other users the specific things
他们需要命名解决，如果我
they need to solve with naming they need
to if I
想要查看您的数据，而um堆栈需要找到您的数据在哪里
want to look at your data um block stack
needs to find where your data is you
知道您正在将数据存储在某些我需要知道的存储服务器上
know you're storing your data on some
storage server somewhere I need to know
您所知道的是使用Amazon AWS或您可能知道的Microsoft Azure，如果是的话
what you know are using Amazon AWS or
maybe Microsoft Azure you know and if so
Microsoft正在破坏哪个服务器，因此会阻止堆栈
which server that Microsoft are
destroying your data so block stack
需要一种将名称映射到存储数据的位置的方法，这就是
needs a way to map names to the location
where you store your data so that's one
他们用名字做的一件大事，但他们也需要找出我是否
big thing that they're doing with names
but they also need to find out if I
要读取您的数据，我需要能够执行诸如检查
going to read your data I need to be
able to do things like check that it's
真的，您知道的数据无法存储，这并不是要说的全部
really your data you know I can't store
not the whole point of this is to not
必须信任存储服务，以便我能够检查它
have to trust the storage services so in
order for me to be able to check it that
这是您的数据，我们需要一种将名称映射到公钥的方法，我们将
it's your data we need a way to map the
name to the public key and we're gonna
假设在存储数据时先使用公钥对其进行签名，因此我们需要
assume that when you store data you sign
it with your public key first so we need
这两个DeMayo都指定要在何处查找此人的数据，并在地图上为公众命名
both DeMayo names to where to find the
person's data and map names the public
我们用来检查检索数据时真正是您真正的数据的密钥
key that we used to check that when we
retrieve data it's really data that you
而不是由存储服务编写的某种误导性的东西
wrote and not some kind of misleading
thing cooked up by the storage service
或其他现在将此人称为公钥的东西
or someone else
now this named a public key thing
如果我想加密数据，那么实际上也以其他方式使用，以便只有你
actually is used in other ways too if I
want to encrypt data so that only you
可以读取它的方式大概是加密数据或某些数据
can read it probably the way I'm gonna
do that is to encrypt the data or some
其他密钥使用您的公共密钥，以便只有您的私有密钥才能读取它，因此如果
other key using your public key so that
only your private key can read it so if
我想实现加密的ACL或几乎所有权限密钥
I want to implement cryptographic ACLs
or really almost any permissions key
访问控制方案，我需要你，我需要给人名
access control scheme I need you have I
need to build the name the people who
可以使用数据，所以如果我要创建访问控制列表，这些是
can use the data and so if I'm gonna
make access control lists these are
通常以名称驱动的一种或另一种方式，并且可能能够命名
usually one way or another
driven by names and may be able to name
可以读取我的数据的人，所以这尤其是映射该部分的人
the people who can read my data so
this in particular this part that maps
公钥的人名，通常通常称为公钥
names of people to public keys this is
usually often called a public key
基础设施或PKI，因此，除了其他提议之外，
infrastructure or PKI and so what block
sac is proposing among other things is a
通用类型的公共全局PKI公共密钥基础结构要映射
general-purpose sort of public global
PKI public key infrastructure to map
用户名给用户的公共密钥，这实际上非常重要，因为
user names to users public keys and this
is actually quite important because
人们几十年来一直知道，为了使
people known for a long time decades
decades that in order to sort of make
互联网安全的巨大进步几乎可以肯定，唯一的方法就是
big advances in Internet security almost
certainly the only way to do that is to
有某种公钥方案，以便人们可以签署您知道的数据
have some sort of public key scheme so
that people can sign you know data that
他们产生电子邮件并检查收到的电子邮件或数据上的签名
they produce email and check signatures
on email or data that they receive for
并加密，以确保对预期的隐私
other people and also encrypt so that to
ensure privacy said on the intended
读者可以是数据，所以几乎任何互联网计划或大型计划
reader can be the data so almost any
internet wide scheme or large scheme
旨在获得加密隐私或加密身份验证的结果
intended to get cryptographic privacy or
cryptographic authentication ends up
必须涉及某种公共密钥系统的公共密钥基础架构
having to involve some sort of public
key system public key infrastructure so
现在我可以确定我想与之交谈的人的身份
that I can find out now given the
identity the person I want to talk to
我如何找到他们的公钥，但是还没有成功的公钥
how do I find their public key and yet
there kind of isn't a successful public
关键的基础架构系统没人真正知道如何构建
key infrastructure system out there
nobody's really figured out how to build
其中之一实际上是有用的，因此人们倾向于不这样做
one of these that's actually useful and
as a result people have tended not to
建立或部署人员倾向于不部署
build or deploy people tended not to
deploy
具有加密隐私和真实性的系统，因为没有PKI和
systems with cryptographic privacy and
authenticity because there's no PKI and
也许是因为人们尚未从事PGI的研究，因为目前尚不清楚
maybe because of that people haven't
worked on PGI's because it's not clear
谁会使用它们，但无论如何要使用块堆栈的原因之一
who would use them but at any rate one
of the reasons why block stack is
有趣的是，因为他们正在努力构建全球规模的公钥
interesting is because they're trying
hard to build a global scale public key
基础设施
infrastructure
名字的名字记得这篇论文谈论的是Zuko的三角形
the kind of names remember the paper
talks about this Zuko's triangle thing
名称的种类本文讨论的名称样式是三种
the kinds of names the style of names
that the paper's talking about is three
这三个有趣的特性之一是它们的独特之处
these three interesting properties one
is their unique and what that really
实际上意味着这些名称具有全局含义，Robert的名字
means actually is that the names have
global meaning that the name Robert for
这个例子的意思是一样的吗
example has the same meaning did it
everyone in the world you know maps to
以相同的方式将相同的数据位置和相同的公用密钥提供给每个人
this in the same way the same data
location same public key to everyone in
当然，这个世界对罗伯特来说有点荒谬
the world of course that's a little
ridiculous for Robert you know
大概我在块堆栈下的ID会比您知道的更长
presumably my ID under block stack would
be much longer than that you know maybe
罗伯特·莫里斯（Robert Morris）有很多罗伯特·莫里斯（Robert Morris），也许我叫罗伯特·莫里斯（Robert Morris）
Robert Morris there's a lot of Robert
Morris's maybe I'm Robert Morris number
67是罗伯特·莫里斯（Robert Morris）向可能会是
67 is Robert Morris to register with
block stack that would probably be
无论如何，更接近我的名字将在区块堆栈下
closer to what my name would be under
block stack anyway that everybody in the
当他们看到此名称并通过PKI运行该名称时
world when they see this name and they
run it through the PKI gets the same
有关它的信息，所以这真的意味着全局可能是一个更好的词
information about it so this really
means global might be a better word for
这是论文所讨论的第二个属性，名字是人类可读的
this the second property the paper talks
about for names are there human readable
就像罗伯特·莫里斯（Robert Morris）一样，有人可以看一看，然后
just like Robert Morris so somebody
could look at it and you know make a
猜一个名字的意思，也许人们可能会记住名字
guess what a name means and maybe people
may be able to remember the names
因为它们具有人类的意义和最后一件事
because they sort of have human
meaningfulness and the final thing
他们感兴趣的是命名系统的名称分配
they're interested in is that the naming
system the allocation of names be
去中心化，你知道纸上的主张是旧的主张
decentralized and you know the paper
claims on this is the old claim that
很难获得所有您知道的三个，因为
it's difficult to get all three you know
apparently not impossible since the
本文是出于某种直觉的原因，而这三个原因很难得到的是
paper does it the sort of intuitive
reason why it's hard to get all three is
如果您假设您的助手分散了，那么没有人
that if you have a supposing you have
assistants decentralized there's no one
您知道的负责很好地分配名称的实体，如果这样做，
entity you know in charge of allocating
names well if you do that then it's very
很难确保唯一性，即如果您没有一些单一实体处理
hard to ensure uniqueness that is if you
don't have some single entity handing
拿出名字你怎么知道自己最终不会拿出相同的名字
out the names how do you know you don't
end up handing out the name same name
如果没有某个中央信任实体，则可以由多个人组成，您可以
the multiple people if there's not some
central trusted entity and you can
实际上有分散的名称
actually have decentralized and unique
names
但是现在最明显的方式是牺牲了人类可读的部分，所以如果
but now the most obvious ways to do that
sacrifice the human readable part so if
您决定自己的名字的是公钥1000位公钥
what you decide your names are are gonna
be you know public keys 1000 bit public
公共私有密码系统中的密钥，任何人都可以组成一个新的
keys in a public private cryptography
system anybody can make up a new
公钥/私钥对通常使用随机数和
public/private key pair they're
typically made use random number and
emmm编号生成器，所以既然任何人都可以弥补，并且生成了
emmm number generator so since anyone
can make one up and they're generated
随机它们将是唯一的，但它们不是人类可读的，所以您知道
randomly they're going to be unique but
they're not human readable so you know
许多明显的方法试图同时获得所有这三个
many of the obvious ways trying to get
all three of these at the same time
效果不是很好，块堆栈在很高的程度上解决了这些问题
don't work so well the way block stack
solves these this at a very high level I
意思是你知道他们会生产去中心化系统，没有
mean you know they're gonna produce
their decentralized system and no
中心人员分发名称，这些名称易于阅读，每个人
central person handing out names the
names are human readable and everyone
从高层次上看到相同的映射集的方法是
sees the same set of mappings the way
they do this at a high level is that
他们依靠比特币的能力来生成单个有序的交易日志
they rely on bitcoins ability to produce
a single ordered log of transactions
这是查看比特币的一种方式，那就是每个人都同意
that's one way of viewing Bitcoin is
that everybody agrees on what the
比特币块的顺序是，你知道也许你会得到临时的叉子，但是
sequence of Bitcoin blocks is and you
know maybe you get temporary Forks but
比特币迅速解决了任何叉子，并使每个人都同意
Bitcoin rapidly resolves any Forks and
causes everyone to agree on what the
块的顺序在比特币中确定，所以一旦我们导致了比特币
sequence of blocks is in Bitcoin ok so
once we a Bitcoin that's causing
关于一系列交易的协议，我们可以坚持，任何人都可以坚持
agreement on a sequence of transactions
we can stick anyone can stick
您知道并且可能有效的比特币日志中的交易
transactions into the Bitcoin log that
you know as well as maybe being valid
比特币交易也隐藏了名称保留记录，因此
Bitcoin transactions also have hidden
away in them name reservation records so
现在，这是对比特币的一种命名
now this is it's a sort of naming on
Bitcoin
您
you
区块链，所以您知道比特币已经投入使用，使我们有点独特
blockchain so you know Bitcoin was
already put getting us sort of unique
以及这些交易区块的全球商定顺序，现在以及任何人
and globally agreed sequence of these
transaction blocks and now and anybody
可以提交交易，因此从某种意义上说，它是完全分散的权利
can submit a transaction so in that
sense it's totally decentralized right
所以如果我想的话，块堆栈使用这种方式命名的方式怎么会
so how wouldn't what the way block stack
uses this for naming is that if I want
注册一个名字，我可以选择任何我喜欢说Robert Morris的名字，只要它是
to register a name I can pick any name I
like say Robert Morris as long as it's
还没有您在使用，我坚持我向比特币提交您知道的交易
not already you in use and I stick in I
submit to Bitcoin a transaction you know
碰巧是有效的比特币交易，但这也将是
that happens to be a valid Bitcoin
transaction but it's also going to be
对阻止堆栈有意义，并且会说请保留，请分配
meaningful to block stack and it's gonna
say please reserve please allocate the
命名RTM并将其映射到我的任何公钥和有关的信息
name RTM and map it to whatever my
public key and my information about
哪里没有人的数据，任何人都可以提交这些数据，并且块堆栈服务器
where to have data not man anyone can
submit these and the block stack servers
所有区块税务服务器都在监视涉及的比特币区块链，
all the blocks tax servers watch the
Bitcoin blockchain as it involves and
每当他们看到这些记录之一时，这也是一个大宗交易
every time they see one of these records
that's a block stack transaction as well
作为比特币交易，区块栈服务器考虑添加此映射
as a Bitcoin transaction the block stack
servers think about adding this mapping
到他们的姓名数据库，但是他们有一套拒绝不良封锁的规则
to their name database but they have a
set of rules for rejecting bad block
在比特币区块链中堆叠交易，例如，如果某些交易失败
stack transactions in the Bitcoin
blockchain so for example if some bad
我自己分配了RTM之后的人请尝试很好地分配RTM
person after I've allocated RTM
themselves try to allocate RTM well they
可以提交他们喜欢的任何交易，这样他们就可以完美地提交
can submit any transaction they like so
they can perfectly well also submit a
交易试图从我那里窃取RTM名称并将其映射到其他名称
transaction trying to steal the name RTM
from me and mapping it to some other
他们知道所有块堆栈服务器的私钥的公钥
public key that they know the private
key for well all the block stack servers
在观看比特币链，只有一个比特币链，并且只有一个
are watching the Bitcoin chain there's
only one Bitcoin chain and only has a
一组内容，所以您所知道的块堆栈服务器
one set of contents and so the block
stack servers as they you know sort of
看看比特币链中的连续交易，将会看到我的
look at successive transactions in the
Bitcoin chain are gonna see my
首先分配，然后他们将看到另一个人的分配
allocation first and then they're gonna
see this other person's allocation for
相同的名称和适用于某个名称的规则已经是Alec
the same name and the rules going to be
well of a name is already Alec
您无法第二次被分配，块堆栈服务器将忽略此设置
you can't be allocated a second time and
the block stack servers will ignore this
试图注册一个名字，所以这里正在实施的是一种
attempted registration of a name so
what's being implemented here is a kind
先分配名字的先来先服务方案
of first-come first-serve scheme for
allocating names the first person to get
就那些分配记录而言，区块链赢得了这个名字
a allocation record into the blockchain
wins that name okay so as far as those
三个属性Zucco三角形属性分散了，因为
three properties the Zucco triangle
properties it's decentralized because
你知道我们可以，我们相信比特币是去中心化的，
you know we can uh we believe that
bitcoin is be decentralized and there's
没有其他实体可以决定谁叫什么名字，实际上就是这样
no sort of other entity deciding who
gets what's name it's really just this
分散的先来先服务方案，名称可以是任何形式
first-come first-served scheme that was
decentralized the names can be anything
没有任何字符串，因此放置它们完全合理
there's no any strings whatever so
they're perfectly reasonable to put
这里的人类可读名称，每个人都在看相同的名称
human readable names in here and
everybody's looking at the same
区块链的任何名字，他们都看到他们都同意第一个
blockchain for any name they all see
they all agree on what the first
该名称的注册非常独特，因此具有全球意义
registration of that name is so it's
unique or globally meaningful as well so
囊囊实际上设法将所有这三个Zucco属性
block sac has managed to actually get
all three of these Zucco properties in
他们的命名系统存在一个问题，这是否意味着块堆栈
their naming system there's a question
does this mean that the block stack
服务器必须从头到尾扫描整个链，以添加新名称
servers have to scan the entire chain
from back to front for adding new names
是的，因此原则上可以确保名称数据库的状态确实是结果
yeah so in principle sure the state of
the name database is really the result
解释整个区块链的过程，但是您当然知道块栈
of interpreting the whole blockchain but
of course you know the block stack
服务器将兑现您所知道的最新状态的现金，因为这些
servers will will cash you know cash the
latest state they've seen and as these
在数据库中，以便每个块堆栈都是您知道的，也许他已经读完了
in a database so each block stacks are
you know maybe he's read this far and
比特币区块链并拥有一个数据库，该数据库具有每个数据库的当前映射
Bitcoin blockchain and has a database
that has the current mapping for every
在此之前的所有框中看到的名称，以及当他们看到比特币的新块时
name seen in all the box before this and
when they see a new block from Bitcoin
他们只会查看事务并逐步更新数据库
they'll just look at the transactions
and update their database incrementally
反映这些交易，从而使新的块堆栈服务器达到最高速度
to reflect these transactions so getting
a new block stack server up to speed
实际上确实需要相当长的时间，我想当我读过一些论文时说
actually does take quite a long time and
I think when some paper I read said it
可能要花费几天的时间，但是一旦您的区块堆栈服务器达到
might take up to a couple of days um but
once your block stack server is up to
速度，然后是各种增量添加
speed then it's all sort of incremental
additions after that
但您知道更重要的一点是，
but you know there's the larger point is
that it is indeed the case that block
堆栈有点背负着比特币，并且您知道您可以轻易地争辩说
stack is kind of piggybacking on Bitcoin
and you know you could easily argue that
比特币最终不是很可扩展，还是使用了太多电力
bitcoin is not very scalable ultimately
or uses that too much electric power who
知道太慢需要很长时间才能反映出新交易和城市
knows what too slow takes a long time to
reflect new transactions and the cities
块堆栈是所有有点不受欢迎的属性
are all sort of somewhat undesirable
properties that block stack is
从比特币继承，但尽管如此，您知道它并不存在
inheriting from Bitcoin but nevertheless
you know it's not there's not aware of
另一种命名方式来获取Zuko的所有三个资产
another way of getting all three of
those Zuko's properties in a naming
系统，因此，如果您重视它们，那么您不会知道很多其他选择
system so if you value them your options
are not you know a lot of options other
比这种方法还好，所以我们可能会问自己这个命名方案是否
than this approach okay so we may ask
ourselves whether this naming scheme
这种将名称映射到公钥和位置以查找数据的方式，无论是
this way of mapping names to public keys
and places to find the data whether it's
它是否真的具有我们真正喜欢的属性，让我们回顾一下
whether it really has properties that we
actually like so let's go back over
这三个属性，因此名称在每个人中都是唯一的
those three properties so one the the
the names are unique everybody in this
系统同意我们的TM表示什么，实际上是全球含义的名称
system agrees on what our TM means it's
really that the names of global meaning
所以问题是我们是否在乎这一点是否很好
so question is whether whether we care
about this whether this is a good
属性，因此您知道其好处的一件事是它使
property so one you know one thing on
the plus side for this is that it makes
这些名字像这个人
that having these names like this human
您知道拥有全球相关名称是否意味着我们可以交谈
you know if that having globally
relevant names means that we can talk
关于彼此的名称，我可以通过电子邮件给您发送一个名称，该名称将包含
about names with each other I can email
you a name and that name will have the
对您和对我来说含义相同，因为我们俩都会在
same meaning for you as it does for me
because we're both gonna look it up in
区块链并获得相同的结果，这很好，这也意味着我
the blockchain and get the same result
and so that's nice it also means that I
可以查看记录在访问控制列表中某处的名称
can look at names that are recorded
somewhere like in an access control list
并且有点了解知道他们会向我走什么
and kind of understand know what they're
going to me
但是有些事情可能不太重要，那就是如果您必须
but some things that are maybe not so
great about this is that if you have to
从一个全局池中选择您的名字，因为这就是我们正在做的
choose your names from a single global
pool because that's what we're doing
在这里，因为只有一个命名系统，所以只有一套
here right the since there's just one
naming system there's just one set of
名称，这意味着实际上很难看一个名字，
names it's gonna mean that it'll be
actually hard to look at a name and
决定它是否是您想要的名字，就像我的名字可能实际上是我一样
decide if it's the name you want like my
name would actually probably be as I
提到之前，您可能知道您知道我们的TM 9五5 8 7
mentioned before you know maybe you know
our TM nine five five eight seven
取决于我们的团队数量，所以这可能是我的名字，实际上
depending on how many our teams are so
this may be my name it's actually very
很难看清楚并决定您真正遇到的RTM是什么，
hard to look at that and decide is that
the RTM that you really met and so that
确实破坏了人类的可读性
really undermines the human readable
他们在这里拥有的财产越大，系统就是那种
property that they have here
the bigger the system is the kind of
具有人类可读名称的价值较低的只是麻省理工学院的人，也许
less valuable having human readable
names is just people at MIT and maybe
也许麻省理工学院只有一个罗伯特·莫里斯（Robert Morris），但实际上
maybe there's only one Robert Morris at
MIT although actually there's more than
一种，但在世界其他地方，这种关心的理由
one but in other across the world the
kind of justification for caring about
他们的名字是人类可读的，我猜是很苗条的
what their names are human readable
that's I guess is very slim it's also a
可读性可能取决于情况，因此如果您
human readable can be deceptive
depending on what's going on so if you
看到一个看起来像您知道麻省理工学院RTM的名称，如果您看到该名称，并且
see a name that looks like you know RTM
at MIT that edu if you see that name and
阻止堆栈或其他可能诱使它连接的东西
block stack or something it's tempting
to imagine that it might be connected to
该电子邮件地址没问题，因为它看起来像人类可读的外观
that email address all right because it
looks as human readable it like looks
就像它的意思一样，拥有人类可读的名称的全部要点是
like it has meaning that's the whole
point of having human readable names is
他们向人们暗示了这四个区块堆叠的意义
that they kind of suggest meaning to
people these four blocks stack that's
深深地误导了一个块堆栈，这些名称真的没有任何意义。
deeply misleading a block stack the
names really don't mean anything it
只需先到先得，先知道这个名字，我们就能知道
simply first-come first-serve so all we
know all we can tell by seeing this name
麻省理工学院的团队从区块堆栈中吸引了您，这是这个名称的意思
our team at MIT de ed you from block
stack is that this is this name means
此名称的第一个人是指注册此名称的第一个人
the first person this name refers to the
first person who registered this name
这就是我们最初所知道的，也许是我可能是其他人，没有
that's all we know initially it might be
me might be somebody else there's no
有理由相信是我或者与MIT或其他任何事物有关
reason to believe it's me or that it's
associated with MIT or anything else all
我们知道，这个名称是由现在第一次注册的人拥有的，如果我
we know is that this name is owned by
whoever registered at first now if I
与拥有这个名字的人建立安全的电子邮件对话
establish say secure email conversation
with whoever owns this name you know
使用会把我们映射到的触发器的键，我花了一些时间与他们交谈
using the key that flops that map's us
to and I spend some time talking to them
你知道也许我最终可以说服自己，他们就是那个人
you know maybe I can eventually
convinced myself that they're the person
我认为他们是谁，但仅此名称就很有意义，但
who I think they are but the name alone
is looks like it's meaningful but
可能不是很有意义，这是人类的真正缺陷
probably is not in fact very meaningful
so that's a real defect in human
可读的名称可能有缺陷，并且
readable names it could be defective and
您知道相关的SEC块命名方案无济于事
you know related
the block SEC naming scheme doesn't help
我发现我是否真的知道我想和谁聊天来阻止麻袋
me find if if I sort of know who I want
to talk to block sacks not really
帮助我会骗我想和你说话的人的名字
helping me will fiying the name of the
person I want to talk to you know I mean
也许您知道您想发送电子邮件给罗伯特·莫里斯，您知道这是
maybe you know you want to send email to
Robert Morris you know gosh this is
毫无帮助，这是块堆栈命名系统中唯一的东西
deeply unhelpful and it's the only thing
in the block stack naming system these
这样的名字，所以不一定解决问题
names that are like this so it's really
not necessarily solving the problem
人们知道，我知道我想与谁交谈
people have which is I know I sort of
know in my head who I want to talk to
但我也不知道他们的公钥，也不知道他们的块栈名称
but I don't know their public key and I
don't know their block stack name either
我如何找到他们的积木技术，所以这是该系统中的一种缺陷
how do I find their blocks technique so
that's a sort of a defect in this system
如果要使用块，您必须真的已经知道名称
you have to really have to already know
the name if you want to use blocks
命名方案，但如何找到这些名称，您可以选择其他选项
naming scheme but how do you find those
names some other options that you could
考虑命名，我在一个系统中属于较大的分散系统
consider for naming I'm in a system the
sort of larger decentralized system one
是我们可以只放弃人们不知道的人类可读名称
is that we could just abandon names
human readable names you know not try to
获得所有这三个Zucco属性，然后直接使用公钥，这样
get all three of those Zucco properties
and just use public keys directly so
这意味着如果我想与您互动，我需要找到您的公钥
that would mean if I want to interact
with you I need to find your public keys
也许您只是将其发送给我，也许您在告诉我一些信息
somehow maybe you just send it to me
maybe you tell me something over the
我可以用来获取您的公钥的电话，也许您向我发送了安全消息或
phone I can use to get your public key
maybe you send me a secure message or
用纸或其他东西写在我们身上，这样我们就可以直接使用public
write on us with the paper or something
so we could just use directly use public
键，然后我们当然不必解决所有这些问题
keys and then we wouldn't have to solve
all these problems although of course
他们很尴尬，但也许我可以将我知道的公钥存储在我的
they're awkward but maybe I can store
the public keys I know about in my
个人联系人列表，它们将对您有所帮助，例如
personal contact list and they'll be
helpful be like telephone numbers of
电话号码没有任何意义，但是一旦我知道了您的电话号码，我就可以
telephone numbers don't mean anything
but once I know your phone number I can
将其保留在我的联系人列表中，另一种可能的方法是放弃
stick it in my contact list another
possible approach would be to abandon
去中心化的部分，然后尝试煮一些中央实体
the decentralized part and just try to
cook up some central entity that would
实际上可靠地验证您知道的某个集中实体的身份
actually reliably verify identity that
some centralized entity you know maybe
发放社会保险号的社会保险系统，或者您知道
the Social Security system that hands
out Social Security numbers or you know
出示驾驶执照的人是谁
whoever it is that hands out driver's
license or something and kind of
背负他们的工作以建立您的集中观念
piggyback on their work to establish a
centralized notion of you
任何种类的经过验证的名称实际上也非常困难，但是
any kind of verified names that's
actually remarkably difficult also but
你知道这是思考的另一条途径，所以块栈把这个
you know it's another avenue to think
about anyway so block stack took this
一种使名字正确的特殊方法，嗯，让我有点
particular approach to try to get names
all right um the let me just kind of
概述块堆栈中的棋子的大图，有点像
outline the big picture of the pieces in
block stack which is sort of a
我之前展示的去中心化应用程序图的改进
refinement of the decentralized
application diagram that I showed before
在底部，他们拥有不断变化的比特币系统
sort of at the bottom they have this
Bitcoin system that's chugging along
带有比特币区块，而这些区块对比特币来说是未知的
with Bitcoin blocks and the carry along
kind of unknown to Bitcoin these blocks
科技交易中，有一堆以块堆栈命名的系统服务器，
tech transactions there's a bunch of
block stack naming system servers and
目前还不清楚他们是否打算让普通人来经营他们还是
it's not really clear whether they
intend ordinary people to run them or
他们将以对普通百姓最有意义的方式提供服务
that they would be a service in a way it
makes the most sense for ordinary people
在他们自己的笔记本电脑上运行它们，因为您必须信任它们，但这可能不会
to run them on their own laptops because
you have to trust them but that may not
无论如何，这些功能都很棒，例如命名服务服务器，请阅读
be so great anyway these blocks like
naming service servers read the
至少在第一个过程中，区块链和一种积累数据库的方式
blockchain and kind of accumulate a
database these at least in the first
例如，区块链中的区块链是公钥，
instance what's in block what's in the
Bitcoin blockchain is public keys and
散列信息的加密散列，描述每个用户的位置
the hash the cryptographic hash of
information describing where each user
存储他们的数据，因为您可以存储该信息，这就是您
stores their data because you could
store that information this is just you
知道Artyom商店是Amazon AWS中的数据之类的东西，但是太大了，无法排序
know Artyom stores is data in Amazon AWS
or something but that's too big to sort
方便地存储比特币，所以有这种中间层
of conveniently store Bitcoin and so
there's this kind of intermediate layer
叫做Atlas，这确实是唯一的工作，就是将
called Atlas it was really it's only job
is to map hashes of information that are
藏起来，比特币进入这些自己的信息
stashed and Bitcoin into these own
information
每个用户一个人的记录，所以这意味着我知道我是否有RT M
one's own record per user and so that
means that my you know if I have an RT M
带有散列的注册和箱钉我的区域记录刚刚有
registration and box tack that holds
with a hash my zone record this just has
名称或您知道的Internet地址或我存储我的位置的东西
the name or the you know Internet
address or something of where I store my
数据，所以可能是您知道AWS斜线知道我以前使用的任何标识符
data so it might be you know AWS slash
know whatever identifier I used to
唯一标识我存储在AWS中的内容，这实际上是对
uniquely identify the stuff that I store
in AWS and this is really a reference to
我的存储所在的位置我所有的键值对现在都存储在这里
my where my storage sits where all my
key value pairs are stored now the paper
我认为论文的愿景是您可以将您的区域记录指向
I think the papers vision is that you be
able to have your zone record point to
实际上，任何云存储都必须
any cloud storage out there
in fact the cloud storage system has to
您知道服从块堆栈接口，因此您不能只在
you know obey the block stack interface
and so you can't just use in the
现有的云存储系统，因此在实践中所有这些都指向
existing cloud storage system so in
practice these all point to block at the
这些区块在gaia伺服器上征税的那一刻，他们就运行这个，而这些仅仅是
moment of these blocks tax on gaia
servers they run this and these are just
知道不同块堆栈用户和存储的存储服务器
storage servers that know about
different block stack users and store
它们的键值对，这意味着我是否要从中读取您的数据
their key value pairs for them and that
means if i want to read your data out of
如果我在要读取您的数据的第二个应用程序中运行
if i'm running in a block second
application that wants to read your data
我需要以某种方式应用你的名字我得找到你的名字，也许你告诉我
i need to apply your name somehow i
gotta find your name maybe you tell me
通过电话输入您的名字我在使用的应用程序中输入您的名字
your name over the phone i type your
name into the application i'm using
也许是做这个经理，过去常常出去找你的待办事项
maybe it's a to do this manager and used
to go out and find your to do list items
告诉我我的应用程序将联系块堆栈命名系统服务器并询问
to show me my app is gonna contact a
block stack naming system server and ask
它翻译成你的名字，一直在看着它保持
it to translate your name it's been
watching the blockchain it keeps a
映射它知道如何使用哈希找到您的区域记录您的区域记录
mapping it knows how to use the hash to
find your zone record your zone record
指向您和Gaia拥有的一些数据，然后我的应用程序会获取这些数据
points to some data owned by you and
Gaia and then my app fetches this data
它需要验证数据，以便所有阻止活动的应用程序期望数据为
it needs to verify the data so all
blocks active apps expect data to be
由所有者在盖亚（Gaia）上签名并使用公钥在
signed by the owner in Gaia and the
public key to check your signature on
您知道的数据我可以使用您的公共密钥或嵌入的公共密钥
the data you know I can use your public
key or public keys embedded and
您的记录和比特币，所以我可以在我的应用程序中使用它，真的可以使用它来检查
your record and Bitcoin and so I can use
it to my app really can use it to check
这里的签名确保这是您实际生成的数据，
the signature here make sure that this
is data that you actually produced and
不是一个不值得信赖的gaya服务器，所以这有点像
not something that an untrustworthy gaya
server okay so that's sort of a basic
它如何工作的概述，事实证明，将它们嵌入
outline of how this works it it turns
out that sort of embedding their
比特币区块链上的信息并不像我描述的那么简单
information on the Bitcoin blockchain is
not as straightforward as I described
他们有他们需要特别的努力来检测叉子
they they have they need to take special
efforts to detect Forks for example
因为它们无法到达名称服务器无法进入的区域
because they don't get to the blocks
that name servers don't sort of get to
直接意识到有一个叉子可以检测到它，我的意思是他们的意思是
realize directly that there's been a
fork that to detect it I mean they means
侦探团因为叉子可能是攻击的一部分，所以您知道比特币
the detective cuz the fork might be part
of an attack and you know the Bitcoin
不会为他们过滤掉不良记录，所以他们必须自己做，
isn't filtering out bad records for them
and so they have to do their own and
将自己的规则强加给他们离开的记录，就像忽略重复记录
force their own rules on the records
they get out like ignoring duplicate
注册那里，他们还发现需要绘制图表以收取费用
registrations there's they also turns
out need to chart they charge fees for
注册一个名称，这意味着比特币交易即
registering a name and that means that
the Bitcoin transaction that is the
名称注册必须向所谓的烧录地址支付一些钱
registration of a name has to pay some
money to what's called a burn address
支付一些比特币当前的比特币到刻录地址，以便拥有正确的权利
pay some Bitcoin current bitcoins to a
burn address in order to have the right
注册该名称，并在以下位置实际检查块堆栈名称服务
to register that name and the block
stack name service actually checked at
每个名称注册交易确实向该烧录地址支付了足够的比特币
each name registration transaction did
pay enough Bitcoin to this burn address
它没有私钥，所以钱只会消失，其原因
for which there's no private key so that
money simply disappears and the reason
他们这样做是因为他们要求每一个名字注册都浪费一些
they do this the reason why they require
every name registration to waste some
钱是这样，否则不好的人只注册很多东西就太容易了
money is that otherwise it's too easy
for bad people to just register lots and
许多名称当然都具有域命名系统的经验
lots of names like certainly the
experience with the domain naming system
有一段时间，那些刚刚注册的人可以免费进行名称注册
where for a while name registration was
free those that people who just register
你知道每个人都知道两个字母和三个字母的组合
you know every single you know one two
and three letter combination that's
可能，他们不会免费拥有所有这些名称，也不会有人知道
possible and they wouldn't own all these
names for free or somebody knowing that
我真的很想拥有RTM可以在我之前注册的名称
I would really like to own the name RTM
might register before me
然后，如果我想使用它，我必须付钱给他们，以便尝试阻止
and then if I wanted to use it I have to
pay them so in order to try to deter
他们有他们需要收费，而这实际上是pulmo
that they have a they require fees and
that's actually pulmo probably an
设计的重要部分，因为互联网上的免费内容往往是
important part of of the design since
free stuff on the internet tends to be
是的，容易被滥用或被淹死
yeah
tends to be abused or sort of drowned
在故意的垃圾邮件中删除了这张图片上的一个细节，所以我省去了
out in intentional spam all right one
detail on this picture so I left out the
这张图片中的爪子，我们让客户端计算机运行一些应用程序，这是
claw in this picture we have the client
machines running some app this is the
现在，当应用程序需要获取我的数据时，客户端设备获取所需的数据
client device now when the app needs to
get out my data get at my data it needs
以便每当将数据写入我的应用程序时将其解密
to be able to decrypt it whenever it
writes data into my guys storage my app
需要能够最终使用我的私钥对其进行加密
needs to be able to encrypt it
ultimately using my private key and when
我将数据取回很不错，以便最终也能以一种方式解密
I fetch data back it nice to be able to
decrypt it also ultimately one way or
另一个使用我的私钥，因此这些应用程序需要使用私钥
another using my private key so these
applications need to get at private keys
但私钥对超级duper敏感，而这些应用是
but private keys are super duper
sensitive and whereas these apps are
就是我从区块堆栈应用商店下载的任何垃圾，甚至可能
just whatever junk I downloaded from the
block stack app store and possibly
完全不可信，所以我们永远都不想给他们一个私钥，所以
totally untrustworthy so we never want
to give them a private key so what
实际发生的是，我一直在运行一个单独的程序
actually happens is that there's a
separate program that I'm always running
叫做块堆栈浏览器，它是这个程序
called the block stack browser and it's
this program
知道我的私钥，因此，如果该应用程序想像我一样做事，
that knows my private key and so if the
app wants to do stuff as me is really
首先要通过块堆栈浏览器来完成它，实际上是这样
got to first do it through the block
stack browser and in fact the way this
地方有这么复杂，块样式浏览器实质上组成
place has so complicated in detail the
block style browser essentially makes up
该应用中每个应用的私钥类型仅使用每个应用的私钥和
kind of per app private key in this app
uses just the per app private key and
不是我真正的主密钥，所以这个应用程序再也不了解我
not my real sort of master private key
so this app again doesn't get to know my
真正的私钥，但是这个问题并未向
real private key but this issue of not
revealing sensitive key material to the
这些应用程序作为一个重要的细节可能确实不值得信赖，
these apps which may be indeed quite
untrustworthy as an important detail and
现在可以将有关我的主私钥的秘密保留在私钥主题上的块
blocks that keeps my master private key
secret now on the topic of private keys
基本上每个您知道的系统（如比特币本身）都存在一个弱点
a weakness in essentially every system
you know like Bitcoin itself and block
堆栈，这也是用户倾向于不像应该注意的那样谨慎
stack and also is that users tend not to
be as careful as they ought to be about
私钥，我是吗，我知道我是否要使用手机中的块堆栈吗
private keys so am i you know if I'm
gonna use block stack from my phone you
知道，这意味着如果我将手机留在手机中，则手机必须知道我的私钥。
know that means my phone has to know my
private key if I leave my phone in the
自助餐厅然后找到它的人现在都有设备
cafeteria
then whoever finds it now has a device
里面有我的私钥，可以像我一样做任何事情，因为到目前为止
that has my private key in it and can do
anything as me because as far as block
攻击担心他们是我，他们知道我的私钥用户也倾向于
attack is concerned they are me they
know my private key users also tend to
丢失私钥，您知道我一段时间不使用该服务
lose private keys you know I don't use
the service for a little while you know
我忘记了保护个人隐私的任何密码短语
I forget whatever passphrase it was for
example that was protecting the private
密钥，或者我将私钥放在USB某人的某处，密钥用于
key or I put my private key on a USB
someone key from somewhere for
妥善保管然后丢失USB密钥，这完全是常规问题，
safekeeping and then lose the USB key so
that's completely routine problem that
用户拥有并阻止攻击实际上并不能真正解决这些问题
users have and block attack actually
does not really have an answer to these
我非常假设问题是用户将对自己的隐私保持谨慎
questions I'm a pretty much assume the
users will be careful of their private
密钥，如果丢失了私钥块，将无法为您找回
keys and if you lose your private key
blocks that can't get it back for you
就像是为了确保超级安全，如果您不必
it's like it's in order to be super
secure in order if you're not to have to
如果您丢失客户端，则只有您的客户端知道您的私钥才能创建信任块堆栈
trust block stack only your client knows
your private key if you lose your client
我们忘记了您是什么意思，您完全不知道
we forget your what are the
phrases you're just completely out of
运气和障碍无法帮助您，所以这实际上是一个困难
luck and blocks that can't help you and
so this is just a difficulty in real
生活中人们不希望使用脆弱且现实生活中的系统
life people don't want to use systems
that are that brittle and in real life
最终发生的是，即使您知道严重的系统
what ends up happening is that even
systems that have you know serious
密码学通常有某种密钥检索方案，因此我可以搅动
cryptography usually have some sort of
key retrieval scheme whereby I can stir
我可以告诉一个大堆的东西，也许是我母亲的娘家姓，或者你知道他们
something I can tell a block stack maybe
my mother's maiden name or you know they
给我发短信到我的电话或任何我可以使用的方案
send me an SMS thing to my telephone or
whatever some scheme I can use to
恢复我的私钥，如果您想攻击系统，通常是
recover my private key and those if you
want to attack a system it's often the
最简单的系统密钥恢复方面的密码恢复
password recovery of the key recovery
aspect of the system that's the easiest
攻击我只是叫一个筹码堆我说我告诉他们你知道我
to attack I just call a block stack I
said I said tell them you know I'm
真的我是罗伯特·莫里斯（Robert Morris），您必须相信我，请您知道我们说过
really I'm Robert Morris you got to
believe me please you know we said
罗伯特·莫里斯（Robert Morris），这对我来说是密码的关键
Robert Morris it's key for me your
password
罗曼告诉我新密码，如果我足够说服您知道的话，
nah man tell me the new password and if
I'm convincing enough you know and the
系统允许Hebe设置他们要让我拥有它，而且他们可能也是
system allows Hebe sets they're gonna
let me have it and they're probably also
大概是攻击者真的在打电话并假装是我
presumably if it's an attacker really
who is calling and pretending to be me
他们会让攻击者重置密钥或任何阻止的密码
they'll let the attacker reset the
password of the key or whatever blocks
碰巧不允许这样做，因为它显然是不安全的，但却是真实的
that happens not to allow that because
it's so obviously insecure but real
世界系统，如果他们不希望其用户放弃他们，则需要拥有一个
world systems if they don't want their
users to abandon them need to have a
更好的计划，还不清楚如何使它更好
better plan and it's not clear how to
make that better all right
好吧，有几种
all right there's a couple of sort of
我想谈论的问题对我来说是系统中的问题
issues I want to talk about that come up
in the system for me the block stack is
确实是一种需要思考的问题源，甚至是
really a kind of source of questions to
think about or even kind of things that
您不太了解您所知道的建议，可用于更多需要处理的事情
are not really well you know suggestions
for use for more things to work on you
知道阻止美国证券交易委员会，我认为现在的性行为是
know block SEC I think black sex
situation now is that you probably
实际上并不想使用它为真实用户构建真实系统，但是
wouldn't actually want to use it to
build a real system for real users but
这是一种尝试，为有朝一日可能足够的系统指明方向
it's kind of trying to point the way to
a system that might someday be if enough
聪明才智投入其中
cleverness was put into it enough
development was done on it might
实际上是一个既方便程序员又方便
actually be a system that was both
convenient for programmers and actually
为用户提供了一些真正的价值，但可能还没有，但是它的入口
provided some real value for users but
probably not there yet but its entrance
想一想，您知道如何设计不同或更好的顺序
to think about you know how it could be
designed differently or better in order
使它更接近真正有用的东西，所以一个问题
to kind of get it closer to something
that were really useful so one question
在to的上下文中，您可能特别想知道是否块堆栈
you might have especially in the context
of a to for is whether block stack
真的需要像这样使用比特币真的不，你不知道
really needs to use Bitcoin like that
points really not you know not that
注册您知道的名称时，您所要支付的费用不菲
great the fees that you have to pay you
know to register a name you know vary in
比特币的价值由以下因素决定：几乎每晚通宵都在
value in Bitcoin by factors of you know
100 almost every night overnight at
此外，人们真的像使用比特币的方式
times in addition people really down the
way like the way Bitcoin you uses
为了确保CPU的安全而消耗CPU的工作量证明，所以您知道比特币不是
proof-of-work to burn up CPU in order to
be secure so you know Bitcoin is not
完美，尽管它是系统的重要组成部分
perfect although it's kind of an
important part of the system otherwise
他们不知道他们不清楚如何在没有名字的情况下命名
they couldn't you know they it's not
clear how they would do names without
整个比特币搭配，所以一个问题，您可能会有八到四个
this whole Bitcoin tie-in and so one
question you might have eight to four is
我是否是证书透明性您知道我们上次看过它
whether I'm certificate transparency
which is a you know we looked at it last
周证书透明度没有采矿没有工作证明
week a certificate transparency does not
have mining does not have proof of work
但是您知道它足够强大，可以在命名系统中提供帮助，因此
and yet you know it's powerful enough to
be helpful in a naming system and so
问题是是否谈到比特币是否可以使用某些东西的盒子
question is whether said of Bitcoin
whether box that could use something
像证书透明度那样
like certificate transparency not in
order to
实施关于名称的适当规则，但实际上不知道答案
enforce adequate rules about names and
actually don't know the answer to that
我的猜测是答案是否定的我的感觉是，尽管证书透明
my guess is the answer's no my feeling
is that while certificate transparency
可以揭示冲突或冲突确实是对注册相同名称的人的一种
can reveal conflicts or conflicts really
is a to people registering the same name
例如，如果您要求所有人将其姓名注册提交给
like if you required everybody to submit
their name registrations to a
证书透明日志是的，的确可以看到两个人
certificate transparency log yes indeed
you would be able to see that two people
注册了相同的名称，但证书透明度无法解决
had registered the same name but
certificate transparency doesn't resolve
所有权冲突，所以如果我注册RT，您应该知道去年我
ownership conflicts so if I register RT
you know supposedly last year I
注册了RT M，第二年我一直在愉快地使用它，然后
registered RT M and I've been using it
happily for the next year and then
有人今天注册了RT M是的，您知道他们会提交他们的
somebody else registers RT M today yeah
you know they'll submit their
注册到证书透明度日志，所以现在也许
registration to a certificate
transparency log and so now maybe that
将使我的名字无法使用或其他名称，但是尚不清楚谁应该拥有
will make my name unusable or something
but it's not clear really who should own
名称，因为证书透明性不是很强大
the name because certificate
transparency doesn't have very powerful
解决这些冲突的机制，您可能会认为顺序是
mechanisms for resolving these conflicts
you might think that order would be
足够但相同的记录和不同的证书透明度日志
enough but the same records and
different certificate transparency logs
可以有不同的顺序，因为没有什么可以强迫不同的
can have different order because there's
nothing forcing the different
透明度日志具有完全相同的顺序，如果您想知道如何
transparency logs to to have exactly the
same order and if you want you know how
比特币可以强制执行您要添加相同顺序的每个区块副本
come Bitcoin can enforce every replica
of the blocks you'd add the same order I
相信答案确实归结为比特币挖矿比特币挖矿
believe the answer to that really boils
down to bitcoins mining bitcoins mining
解决Forks的问题解决延迟区块链的副本和
that resolves Forks it resolves
deferring copies the blockchain and
强制达成协议，如果您不进行采矿，至少您知道或有所了解
forces agreement and if you don't do
mining at least you know or something
像挖掘一样，不清楚如何在订单上添加强制协议
like mining it's it's not that clear how
to add a enforce agreement on the order
的记录，所以另外，块堆栈收费可能是
of the records so in addition the fees
the block stack charges are probably
避免在命名系统中出现各种垃圾邮件的关键
critical to avoid various kinds of spam
in the naming system various kinds of
滥用，您知道基于比特币构建的区块堆栈可以自动进行排序
abuse and you know block stack built on
Bitcoin can sort of automatically
要求人们付款以注册基于证书透明性的块堆栈
require people to pay to register block
stack built on certificate transparency
你知道没有直接的机制需要
you know
there's no direct mechanism to require
费用，实际上，我认为这里的要点实际上更大了，
fees and in fact that I think the point
here is actually quite a bit larger and
那就是很多人谈论使用区块链处理很多东西
that's that a lot of people talk about
using blockchains for lots of stuff
除了加密货币，但实际上似乎很难使用开放式区块链
other than cryptocurrency but in fact it
seems difficult to use blockchains open
具有不受限制的访问权限的区块链，除非它们与某些
block chains with unrestricted access
except when they're coupled with some
那种加密汽车加密货币再次我不知道
kind of crypto car
cryptocurrency again I don't know if
没错，但这肯定是我的印象，所以是一个大问题
that's true but it's certainly my
impression all right so a big question
块堆栈是它是否对程序员和
with block stack is whether it's going
to be convenient for programmers and to
我这个问题绝对关键，因为它是两个非常重要的问题之一
me the this questions absolutely
critical because it's one of two very
另一个关键问题是另一个问题
critical questions the other one is the
other critical question is whether it
让用户生活得更好我目前的看法是
框AK对于程序员来说并不是特别方便，我认为我已经使用块
box AK is not particularly convenient
for programmers I think I've used block
堆栈一个程序块堆栈，我尝试构建系统来喜欢它，而且我很坚强
stack a program block stack I've tried
to build system to like it and my strong
印象是，在其上构建Web应用程序要困难得多
impression is that it's just a lot more
difficult to build a web application on
这些分散式平台之一，而不是普通平台，
one of these decentralized platforms
than it is on the ordinary platform and
您知道这是一种破坏，因为如果网站开发人员不在
董事会，那么没有人会得到很大的吸引力，如果网站开发人员
board then nobody's gonna get a lot of
traction and if the website developers
不喜欢您知道我有点觉得系统难以编程
don't like you know I sort of feel that
the system is difficult to program the
唯一吸引您的方法就是吸引用户
only way that you're ever gonna get any
traction is if the attraction to users
如此强大以至于您知道用户需要分散的应用程序，并且
这可能会迫使程序员使用它，但是程序员只是在说
that might force programmers to use it
but the programmers just speaking for
我自己的猜测是，基本上所有
代码位于客户端中，我们没有特别的网站，您知道
code is sitting in the client and we
don't have special you know website
服务器非常痛苦，很难拥有特定于
servers is just pretty painful it's hard
to have data that's specific to the
应用程序，因为所有数据都归用户所有，所以很难拥有索引，否则您
application because all data is owned by
users it's hard to have indices or you
知道喜欢的次数或投票，您知道首页排名的种类
know counts of likes or vote
you know the kind of front page rankings
正如我在Reddit或黑客新闻中提到的那样，很难，有各种各样的东西
as I mentioned for reddit or hacker news
are difficult there's all kinds of stuff
如果您对网站本身及其网站的概念一无所知，那将是一个痛苦。
it's a pain if you don't have a notion a
notion of the website itself with its
拥有数据，访问控制实际上同样令人痛苦，这非常容易
own data this the access control is
actually equally painful it's very easy
编写代码和传统网站来决定谁可以看到什么
to write the code and a traditional
website to decide who gets to see what
分散系统中的数据，实际上您只能使用
data in a decentralized system and
really you only can be enforced using
密码访问控制或这些就是示例中显示的方式
cryptographic access control or these
that's the way it seems from the example
一个块栈，除了非常简单的样子
a block stack and it just turns out for
all except for very straightforward like
一名用户使用加密技术使用自己的私人数据来强制访问
one user using their own private data
using cryptography to enforce access
好吧，那真的很痛苦
well it's just pretty painful
所以程序员可能只会在用户兴奋的情况下才会兴奋，因此我们的用户会
so programmers might only be excited if
users were excited so our users gonna be
兴奋，您知道一种看待该问题的方法是
excited you know one way to look at that
one way to ask that question is whether
这种分散使用自己的存储空间有利于用户隐私，因为
this kind of decentralized use your own
storage is good for user privacy because
最大的亮点之一是，通过将数据存储在存储服务上，
that's one of the big pitches is that by
storing data on storage services the
用户拥有并为您付款，这也许会使数据更私密
users own and pay for you know maybe
that'll keep the data more private more
比将其数据存储在网站上更安全，所以我真正要问的是
secure than storing their data on
websites so that really am I asking is a
比信任Facebook或Google更好地保护我的数据不受保护
better than trusting Facebook or Google
to keep my data private both from
Facebook员工以及网站其他用户和黑客
Facebook employees and from other users
of the site and from hackers you might
尝试闯入，这只是一个问题，你知道这取决于
try to break in and that's just a
question right you know sort of depends
您对Facebook的信任程度如何，事实是您仍在存储数据
on how much you trust Facebook the fact
is that you're still storing your data
在云上使用某些服务，也许不是Facebook，而您仍然
out there in the cloud on some service
just maybe not Facebook and you're still
在您的客户端上运行大概由Facebook提供给您的软件
running software on your client that is
presumably provided to you by Facebook
所以您正在运行Facebook软件，而您的客户端则知道是这样，因此您正在
so you're running Facebook software and
your client you know it's so you're
还是有点相信这个，facebook给您或任何地方的这段代码
still kind of trusting this this this
code that facebook gives you or wherever
您从中获取代码，并且您知道我们中间真正的黑客，
you get your code from and you know for
the real hackers among us you can look
在代码上并说服自己，因为您是自己运行它
at the code and convince yourself
because you're running it on your own
电脑，可以满足自己的需求，但是对于普通大众
computer and can meet yourself
okay but for the general public you know
在他们的网站上与Facebook的网络软件交谈之间的区别
the difference between talking to
Facebook's web software on their web
服务器和我名字的Facebook软件以及他们自己的客户端可能看起来不太
server and my name's Facebook software
and their own client may not seem very
太好了，谁知道您正在运行的Facebook应用正在发送
great and who knows maybe the Facebook
app you're running is sort of sending
有关您要监视您的活动的Facebook信息存在一个问题
Facebook information about what you're
up to snooping on you there's a question
关于明智的密码访问控制使程序员感到痛苦，这是一种方法
about wise cryptographic access control
painful for programmers um one way of
看它是访问控制检查您必须做的一种
looking at it is that the access control
checks that you have to do in a sort of
标准的网站非常简单，您只需写一点
standard web site are very
straightforward you just write a little
一点Python代码，或者决定是否应该有一些用户能够使用的代码
bit of Python code or whatever it is to
decide whether some user should be able
查看一些数据，甚至可以使用用户
to see some data and you can even
compute using data that the user
只要您不向用户显示，就不会看到
shouldn't see as long as you don't
reveal it to the user
而在除了简单情况之外的任何情况下，都需要对
whereas in anything but simple
situations doing the cryptography to
允许一些用户但不能让其他用户获取您的数据，这只需要很多
allow some users but not others to get
out your data it just requires a lot
再想一想，所以您知道麻省理工学院注册商会维护所有
more thought so you know suppose the MIT
registrar maintains a list of all the
人们参加8到4的比赛，如果是这样的话，他们会维持这个名单，而我
people taking 8 to 4 and if so as a
group so they maintain that list and I
想要使用它来管理对存储在其中的某些文件的保护
want to use it in order to govern the
protections for some file stored in
具有密码保护和块堆栈的，因为它列出了
Krypton with cryptographic protection
and block stack because that lists that
八到四个学生的小组名单可能会改变，您知道我的工作
group list of eight to four students may
change you know the what I do for
加密可能也必须更改，所以我知道是否加密我可以加密
encryption may have to change too so I
you know if I encrypt I could encrypt
用a至4组列表中的每个用户的密钥对数据进行一次处理，然后
the data once with the key of each user
in the a to four group list and that
之所以能够工作，是因为他们可以读取为他们加密的副本，但是
would work because they could just read
the copy that was encrypted for them but
然后在添加用户时，注册服务商将列表更改为或删除
then as users are added that the
Registrar changes the list as or deletes
用户我需要我的软件我需要注意
users
I need my software I needs to notice
该列表已更改，并且忙于出去并更改内容的方式是
that that list has changed and busily go
out and change the way stuff is
加密，我们为新用户加密，为旧用户删除两个副本
encrypted we encrypt for the new users
deleting two copies for the old users
就像是某种程度的破坏或某种程度的复杂性
and that's just like a level of damage
that or a level of kind of complexity
在当前系统中不存在，不一定就无法完成
that doesn't exist in current systems
not necessarily they can't be done
但是它确实需要很多通常不需要的机械
but it just does require a lot of
machinery that is not ordinarily needed
从用户的角度来看，另一种信任问题是
all right another sort of trust issue
from the point of view of users is that
他们仍然必须信任其存储提供商来保留其数据，并且他们
they still have to trust their storage
provider to preserve their data and they
仍然信任他们的存储提供商始终提供最多的服务
still have just trust their storage
provider to always serve up the most
作弊存储提供者可能会尝试通过以下方式导致最近的版权问题：
recent copy right the cheating storage
provider might try to cause trouble by
提供旧版本，因此我们在该区块堆栈设计中出租，您知道您在
serving up an old version so we lease in
that block stack design you know you're
真正信任您的存储服务器，这种中央服务是从您的角度出发
really trusting your storage server this
central service is from your point of
查看对数据执行正确的操作以保存数据以备份到
view to do the right thing with your
data to preserve it to back it up to
当要求时产生它，当要求时产生正确的版本，这是一个
produce it when asked for to produce the
right version when asked for and it is a
对于普通人来说，如果您信任亚马逊，就会有一个问题
bit of a question for just ordinary
people that if you're trusting Amazon
AWS可以正确存储您的数据而不会丢失它，这并不是一个更大的
AWS to store your data correctly and not
lose it it's not that much bigger of a
相信亚马逊本身就能运行该网站，您知道我们可以争论
step to trust Amazon itself to run the
website and you know we can argue about
它确实是真的，但我想您从高层次上知道
with it that's really exactly true but I
think you know from a high-level point
从大多数人的角度来看，最普通的人确实很小
of view from most people most ordinary
people it's really a pretty pretty small
区别，您必须克服这一点才能说服
distinction and you would have to
overcome that in order to persuade
那个男孩，您知道使用Amazon作为存储的块堆栈方法
people that boy you know the block stack
approach of using Amazon as a storage
服务比使用亚马逊作为网站的标准方法更好
service is better than the standard way
of using Amazon as a website another
从用户角度出发的问题另一个为什么分散的观点
question from users point of view
another pitch for why that decentralized
架构可能对用户更好，因为它可以使他们更好地控制
architecture might be better for users
is that it gives them more control over
您所了解的不是隐私，而是他们与他们一起使用哪些应用程序
over you know not privacy but just sort
of what applications they use with their
数据，因此如果您要切换应用程序但仍使用相同的数据
data so if you want to switch
applications but still use the same data
就像我原则上提到的更改照片编辑应用程序一样
like change photo editing apps like I
mentioned in principle that should be
这种分散的应用程序架构会更容易，因为您知道
easier with this sort of decentralized
app architecture because the you know
如果您要使用该数据，则该数据也不归应用程序网站所有
the again the data is not owned by the
application website if you want to use
我想在多个不同应用程序中使用相同的数据
the same data in multiple different
applications like I want to
日历应用程序，但使用我电子邮件应用程序中的相同数据
a calendar app but use the same data
from my email app that also is you know
分散方案相对方便，因为数据是
relatively convenient with the
decentralized scheme because the data is
再次独立于您可能知道用户想要的应用程序
sort of again independent from the
applications you know maybe users want
这也许他们可能不在所有人名单的首位，并且有一个
this maybe they don't probably not at
the top of anybody's list and there's an
另一个问题是，即使要实现这一愿景，也必须存在
additional problem that in order even
for that vision to work there has to be
文件格式的很多标准化，所以您知道日历文件
a lot of standardization of formats of
files so you know the calendar file my
日历程序必须以我的电子邮件格式存储其日历数据
calendar program has to store its
calendar data in a format that my email
程序可以理解，否则将不起作用，并且如果我要切换
program can understand otherwise that
doesn't work and if I'm gonna switch
电子邮件应用程序很好我的旧电子邮件应用程序最好是存储我的
email applications well my old email
application better have been storing my
以我的新电子邮件应用程序可以理解的格式发送电子邮件
email in a format that my new email
application can understand otherwise
这种去中心化应用程序的愿景我无法轻松切换
this vision of decentralized apps me
easy to switch among can't be made to
成为现实，让我担心这件事的最后一个问题是，这不是
come true a final issue that worries me
about this whole thing is that it's not
明确的是，如果人们愿意为自己的存储付费
clear that users are going to be willing
to pay for their own storage if people
不愿意为我的存储付费，那么整个安排就是
aren't willing to pay for that I'm
storage then this whole arrangement is
没什么吸引力，因为很多要点是给用户更多
pretty unattractive because a lot of the
point was to sort of give the users more
我认为大概是他们自己存储用户的责任
responsibility over their own storing
their own stuff users of I think or so
使用免费的广告广告支持的服务，他们可能会
used free advertise advertisements
supported services that they just might
不愿意花钱购买互联网东西
not be willing to get on board with with
paying for internet stuff
好吧，不过我觉得这整个领域值得你知道
alright nevertheless I feel like this
whole area is you know well worth
密切关注也许值得在它的不同部分上进行工作以
keeping an eye on maybe even worth sort
of working on different pieces of it to
有兴趣寻找研究问题，但是我不
be are interested in looking for
research problems and well I don't
由于我概述的原因，我现在真的相信它，这是
really believe it right now for the
reasons that I outlined I think it's
绝对值得追求，因为总有一天，如果像这样肯定
absolutely worth pursuing because
someday if like definitely the way this
这类分散系统的工作已经越来越好，并且可能
these kinds of decentralized systems
work has been getting better and may
最终足以使竞争激烈
eventually be good enough that that
there's serious competition for
现有的网站架构，如果真的那么认真，我会喜欢的
existing website architectures and I
would just love it if if such serious
这样的竞争就可以了
competition like that were to arise all
right
这就是我下周二要说的最后一堂令人惊异的会议
that's all I have to say next Tuesday
the last class amazing meeting is going
做项目介绍，这样我就可以听到每个人都没有的东西
to be project presentation so I'll get
to hear what what everybody who hasn't
一直在做第四个实验，请问我问题
been doing lab four has been up to
please ask me questions if you have